<library name="ImageResources">
	<description>
		Library for loading image resources. Also abstracts auto-image sheet/atlas resources.
	</description>
	
	<namespace name="ImageResources">
		<class name="ImageResource">
			<description>
				Represents an image.
				Generally, this class cannot do much on its own (aside from querying width and height), 
				and is meant to be used in a secondary library such as Graphics2D or ImageEncoder.
			</description>

			<function name="(constructor)">
				<description>
					Creates a new image resource with the given size.
					To load an existing image from the program's embedded resources, see ImageLoader.
					To load an existing image from an image sheet declared in the build file, see ImageSheet.
				</description>
				<arg name="width" type="int" description="Width of the image in pixels."/>
				<arg name="height" type="int" description="Height of the image in pixels."/>
			</function>

			<function name="getWidth">
				<description>Gets the width of the image in pixels.</description>
				<returns type="int" description="image width"/>
			</function>

			<function name="getHeight">
				<description>Gets the height of the image in pixels.</description>
				<returns type="int" description="image height"/>
			</function>
		</class>

		<class name="ImageLoader">

			<description>
				Loads an ImageResource from the program's compile-time embedded resources.
			</description>

			<function name="loadFromResourcesAsync" static="true">
				<arg name="resourcePath" type="string" description="Path to the image resource."/>
				<returns type="ImageResources.ImageLoader" description="A reference to a new loader object."/>
				<description>
					Loads a compile-time image resource asynchronously and returns the loader object that can be queried for
					status or the final result.
					To check load progress, use .isDone().
					To get the image after loading is complete, use .getImage().
					To load an image synchronously and get an ImageResource instance directly, use .loadFromResources().
					This function cannot be used for image resources that are consolidated into an image sheet, 
					in which case, the ImageSheet class must be used instead for loading. 
				</description>
			</function>

			<function name="loadFromResources" static="true">
				<arg name="resourcePath" type="string" description="Path to the image resource."/>
				<returns type="ImageResources.ImageResource" description="An image resource object."/>
				<description>
					Loads a compile-time image resource synchronously and returns it.
					To load an image asynchronously, use .loadFromResourcesAsync().
					This function cannot be used for image resources that are consolidated into an image sheet, 
					in which case, the ImageSheet class must be used instead for loading. 
				</description>
			</function>

			<function name="isDone">
				<returns type="boolean" description="true if loading is complete"/>
				<description>
					Returns true if the image has finished loading.
				</description>
			</function>

			<function name="getImage">
				<returns type="ImageResources.ImageResource" description="The image"/>
				<description>
					Returns the image once loading is complete. 
					Code must call .isDone() before calling this method.
					Even if the image has finished loading, this function will throw a 
					Core.InvalidOperationException if .isDone() was never called. 
				</description>
			</function>
		</class>

		<class name="ImageSheet">

			<description>
				An image sheet is a collection of image resources.
				The way the images are aggregated is defined by the build file.
				By aggregating images, loading images from disk is generally faster as it reduces the number
				of hard disk reads (or in the case of JavaScript, image download requests). 
				Furthermore, OpenGL based platforms can load all the images into a single texture atlas
				to prevent texture context switches.
				If there are lots of images to load, this simplifies the process of providing a progress bar since
				the completion percentage is calculated by the library. 
				All ImageResources that are loaded from an image sheet abstract the aggregation away from your code
				such that operations will appear as though the image is a standalone image file.
			</description>

			<function name="loadFromResources" static="true">
				<arg name="idOrIds" type="string|list-of-string" description="An image sheet ID or a list of image sheet IDs"/>
				<returns type="ImageResources.ImageSheet" description="An image sheet"/>
				<description>
					Returns a new image sheet object.
					If multiple sheet ID's are passed to this method, all those image sheets will be aggregated 
					into one single ImageSheet instance.
					This function will block execution of your program until loading has completed which 
					can potentially be very slow. 
					To load asynchronously, use .loadFromResourcesAsync().
				</description>
			</function>

			<function name="loadFromResources" static="true">
				<arg name="idOrIds" type="string|list-of-string" description="An image sheet ID or a list of image sheet IDs"/>
				<returns type="ImageResources.ImageSheet" description="An image sheet"/>
				<description>
					Returns a new image sheet object which is not completely loaded yet.
					If multiple sheet ID's are passed to this method, all those image sheets will be aggregated 
					into one single ImageSheet instance.
					To check to see if the image sheet is done loading, use .isDone().
					To check the progress of loading, use .getProgress().
				</description>
			</function>

			<function name="getImage">
				<arg name="resourcePath" type="string" description="Path to an image resource"/>
				<returns type="ImageResources.ImageResource" description="An image resource"/>
				<description>
					Returns an image resource that is contained in this image sheet.
					If the image sheet is loaded asynchronously, this method cannot be called without
					calling .isDone() first, even if the image sheet has finished loading.
				</description>
			</function>

			<function name="isDone">
				<returns type="boolean" description="true if the image sheet is done loading"/>
				<description>
					Returns true if the image sheet is done loading. 
					This method is only applicable to asynchronously-loaded image sheets.
					This method must be called for all asynchronous image sheets before getImage() is called,
					otherwise an InvalidOperationException is thrown, even if the image sheet is actually done loading.
				</description>
			</function>

			<function name="getProgress">
				<returns type="float" description="Ratio of progress"/>
				<description>
					Returns a ratio of loading progress from 0 to 1.
					This is a convenience method for showing progress to the user, but .isDone() must still be called
					before accessing any image resources.
				</description>
			</function>

			<function name="getFiles">
				<returns type="list-of-string" description="List of all image resource paths in this sheet."/>
				<description>
					Returns a list of all the image resource paths available in this image sheet.
				</description>
			</function>
		</class>
		
		<class name="ImageNotFoundException">
			<description>Exception thrown when an image path does not exist.</description>
			<field name="path" type="string" description="Path of the image which was being attempted to load"/>
		</class>
		
		<class name="SheetNotFoundException">
			<description>Exception thrown when an image sheet with a given ID does not exist.</description>
			<field name="id" type="string" description="ID of the image sheet that does not exist"/>
		</class>
		
		<class name="LoadFailedException">
			<description>Exception thrown when an image fails to load. The exception message field may contain more information.</description>
		</class>
		
	</namespace>
</library>