<documentation>
	<library name="FileIO">
		<description>
			Library for interacting with the local disk or virtualized disks.
		</description>
		<namespace name="FileIO">
			<namespace name="File">
				<function name="readText">
					<arg name="filepath" type="string">Path to a text file to read, either absolute or relative.</arg>
					<description>
						Reads the contents of a text file and returns it as a string.
					</description>
				</function>
				<function name="writeText">
					<arg name="filepath" type="string">Path to a file to write.</arg>
					<arg name="content" type="string">Value to write to the file.</arg>
					<description>
						Writes a value to a file. If the file exists, it will be overwritten. 
						Content overwrites all previous contents (does not append).
					</description>
				</function>
			</namespace>
			<namespace name="Directory">
				<function name="current">
					<description>
						Returns a string indicating the path of the current working directory, which is 
						the starting point of all relative path inputs to other FileIO functions.
					</description>
				</function>
				<function name="list">
					<arg name="filepath" type="string">Path of a directory.</arg>
					<description>
						Lists all the files and directories in the given directory.
					</description>
				</function>
			</namespace>
			<namespace name="Path">
				<function name="isDirectory">
					<arg name="path" type="string">Path to a file or directory.</arg>
					<description>
						Returns a boolean indicating whether the given path is a directory or not.
					</description>
				</function>
				<function name="exists">
					<arg name="path" type="string">Path to a file or directory.</arg>
					<description>
						Returns a boolean indicating whether the given path exists as either a file or directory.
					</description>
				</function>
				<function name="join">
					<arg name="pathSegments" type="string list">List of strings that represent a path</arg>
					<description>
						Joins the strings in the list with the current platform's directory separator character. 
						Generally this is either '/' or '\'. 
					</description>
				</function>
			</namespace>
			<namespace name="UserData">
				<description>
					This namespace contains functionality similar to the <link see="fileio">FileIO</link> namespace as a whole. However all
					operations are applied to the user's application data directory. For Windows users, this is a folder that is created
					at "C:\Users\{username}\AppData\Roaming\{project ID}" where the project ID is defined in the build file. For Linux
					and Mac users, this is the "~/.{project ID}" folder. For non-native platforms, operations are applied to a virtualized
					disk that is backed by some sort of persistent storage. For JavaScript, this is a fake file system implemented over the
					<link url="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/Window/localStorage">localStorage</link> API. The current directory
					is considered to be the root of this user data directory and all relative path access outside of this directory (such as using ../)
					is prevented and will result in an error.
				</description>
				<namespace name="File">
					
				</namespace>
				<namespace name="Directory">
					
				</namespace>
				<namespace name="Path">
					
				</namespace>
			</namespace>
		</namespace>
	</library>
</documentation>
